<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Synced on Glyphack</title><link>https://glyphack.com/synced/</link><description>Recent content in Synced on Glyphack</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://glyphack.com/synced/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Antifragile</title><link>https://glyphack.com/s/antifragile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glyphack.com/s/antifragile/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Coders at Work</title><link>https://glyphack.com/s/coders-at-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glyphack.com/s/coders-at-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>I found interesting interviews in this book.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Jamie Zawinski (he also appears in this documentary &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Q7FTjhvZ7Y">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Q7FTjhvZ7Y&lt;/a>)
Brendan Eich
Peter Norvig&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Live</title><link>https://glyphack.com/s/how-to-live/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glyphack.com/s/how-to-live/</guid><description>&lt;h2 class="heading" id="review">
Review
&lt;a class="anchor" href="#review">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I loved this book. The book promised &amp;ldquo;27 conflicting answers and one wierd conclusion&amp;rdquo; and it delivered it word by word.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can live by following almost any idealogy. They are good when you start it and end up as poor decisions when taken into extreme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everybody hears this as a child.&lt;br>
What makes this book different is that it describes the life following only one belief.&lt;br>
To me this was like a wake up call, because I realized how I was missing out on some ideas because I thought there are right and wrong ways to live.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is smart to plan for short term, making sure you are in a good position now.&lt;br>
It is also smart to plan for the long term, making sure you end up in a good position.&lt;br>
It is good to live for yourself, being able to fulfill your own needs.&lt;br>
It is good to live with others, provide and receive goods.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While reading it I realized that I liked different answers that are conflicting. So what I wanted was conflicting.&lt;br>
This book motivated me to try ideas that I would not try otherwise, because there is no way to live.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to revisit these answers from the book:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Let randomness rule&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Make a million mistakes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Intertwine with the world&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Do nothing&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>How to Win Friends and Influence People</title><link>https://glyphack.com/s/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glyphack.com/s/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people/</guid><description>&lt;p>I found this book in the street.
I wish I could say it changed my life, sadly that would be an exaggeration.
I started reading it and found the stories entertaining. However none of the stories mentioned in the book stick with me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It reminds some things that people forget easily.
So far I&amp;rsquo;m being nicer to people. Say hello and smile. Let them talk and be a good listener.
I think the entire point of this book is to not forget about other people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall it did not provide new insights. I think I&amp;rsquo;ve heard all the tips about letting people talk about themselves and looking through lens of others. I also skipped some little parts as I found it repetitive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if it&amp;rsquo;s not full of new insights why bother reading it? Well there are a few reasons.
The book was filled with stories it helps to feel more connection to the advice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example one advice from the book is to let others talk.
This is hard to apply but the book shows why you should let others talk during conflicts. Why you should let someone talk to make friends.
These examples help the advice to stick.
Of course it needs practice. For me the practice was to notice how often I and others fail at this simple thing.
I&amp;rsquo;ve interacted with a lot of people who cut you in the middle of your story to mention something.
I intentionally refrained myself from mentioning stuff when someone is telling a story.
Try it and you see it&amp;rsquo;s very tempting.
When someone is telling something and calls something with a wrong name, you can still listen to the story and then correct the name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall I&amp;rsquo;m happy I picked up the book on that day. I think everyone should read it. Either to hear the advices or to be reminded about them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Masters of Doom</title><link>https://glyphack.com/s/masters-of-doom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glyphack.com/s/masters-of-doom/</guid><description>&lt;p>The story of [[John Carmack|John Carmack]] and [[John Romero|John Romero]] is entertaining, dramatic and inspirational.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the book also motivates you.
Since you see how much challenges they overcome to make it all work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The book starts by describing two young boys with video game addiction who end up in a well situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They used their work computers over the night to create games that was impossible before they created them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also got the other book [[The Doom Guy|The Doom Guy]] it&amp;rsquo;s the same story but written by [[John Romero|John Romero]].
Mostly because in this book there&amp;rsquo;s a funny story that the two johns get into a fight because Carmack was working 14 hours a day and Romero was not working as much and Romero leaves the company.
I want to know the other side of story as well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Surely You're Joking, Mr. Feynman!</title><link>https://glyphack.com/s/surely-youre-joking-mr.-feynman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glyphack.com/s/surely-youre-joking-mr.-feynman/</guid><description>&lt;p>Fantastic Book. This book shows the true meaning of a curios person.
I love curios people. I also love nonchalant people. Feynman is both.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The peak of this book happened in the &amp;ldquo;O americano, outra vez!&amp;rdquo; chapter for me.
Feynman stayed for a year in Brazil. And found out that they did not have real science.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Have you got science? No! You have only told what a word means in terms of other words.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I never looked at it this way. I have had this experience that a lot of people who are competent on the paper are not competent in actual work.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what is the cause or how to describe it.
This is the perfect description. Some people think knowledge is defining a word in terms of other words.
It&amp;rsquo;s not the words are only useful when you actually know the concept.
Knowing means experienced it.
And most of the learning materials on the internet in this category. They just tell you more words to understand a word.
Maybe to learn something you have to, do it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another story about people and understanding is when he&amp;rsquo;s at the Nobel ceremony.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>She turned to me and said, &amp;ldquo;Oh! You&amp;rsquo;re one of the Nobel-Prize-winners.
In what field did you do your work?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;In physics,&amp;rdquo; I said.
&amp;ldquo;Oh. Well, nobody knows anything about that, so I guess we can&amp;rsquo;t talk about it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;On the contrary,&amp;rdquo; I answered.&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s because somebody knows something about it that we can&amp;rsquo;t talk about physics. It&amp;rsquo;s the things that nobody knows anything about that we can discuss. We can talk about the weather; we can talk about social problems; we can talk about psychology; we can talk about international finance&amp;ndash;gold transfers we can&amp;rsquo;t talk about, because those are understood&amp;ndash;so it&amp;rsquo;s the subject that nobody knows anything about that we can all talk about!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In the first chapters from his childhood to university there are stories about how got interested in many subjects.
He did experiments on ribosomes in biology labs during his time at MIT.
I think everyone has this invisible force that keeps them from going into other fields the way Feynman did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He says hypnotism is interesting because when someone is performing it on you, you don&amp;rsquo;t think anything is happening until it actually happens.
You keep telling yourself that you are aware of the situation and can walk out at any moment until you cannot.
Which is funny because most things in life sound like that.
You tell yourself something is easy I can do it.
Or you can easily change something but you just don&amp;rsquo;t want it.
But in the end until you actually try to do it you don&amp;rsquo;t understand you cannot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He was at Los Alamos during WW2. He became famous for cracking all the locks and safes there.
This story was the funniest. The combination of him just chasing curiosity and defeating all these people who&amp;rsquo;s job was to secure safes is funny.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>System Design Interview</title><link>https://glyphack.com/s/system-design-interview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glyphack.com/s/system-design-interview/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started this book not to prepare for interviews but to learn about this concept of system design.
I was new to the topic so thought getting this book would be good. Especially because the author has been doing this for some time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After reading through the book I found that it is only useful for interviews. It actually helped me with a system design interview.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think it worth reading. Unless you are starting out and have an interview coming up and want to prepare for it the night the interview.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The alternative is books like [[Architecture of open source applications &amp;amp; 500 lines or less|Architecture of open source applications &amp;amp; 500 lines or less]] books that give practical examples of how to create applications.
Also doing is more important than just reading in this topic. You can easily say &amp;ldquo;X does not scale&amp;quot;just because you read it, it&amp;rsquo;s not true.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tech Resume Inside Out</title><link>https://glyphack.com/s/tech-resume-inside-out/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glyphack.com/s/tech-resume-inside-out/</guid><description>&lt;p>It was a good and light read. I picked it up while I was preparing my resume for job searched and I think it was the last thing I read on writing resumes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It can replace reading blog posts online about how to write a resume or resume builder websites.
It does not contain any fluff. You can read it before you write your resume and it contains good advice.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The practice of Programming</title><link>https://glyphack.com/s/the-practice-of-programming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glyphack.com/s/the-practice-of-programming/</guid><description>&lt;p>Picked this up because of the authors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Do You Care What Other People Think?</title><link>https://glyphack.com/s/what-do-you-care-what-other-people-think/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glyphack.com/s/what-do-you-care-what-other-people-think/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Where Good Ideas Come From</title><link>https://glyphack.com/s/where-good-ideas-come-from/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glyphack.com/s/where-good-ideas-come-from/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Write an Interpreter in Go</title><link>https://glyphack.com/s/write-an-interpreter-in-go/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://glyphack.com/s/write-an-interpreter-in-go/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nice book. I think I would have learned a lot from it if I read it before writing a compiler. The content were what I knew already.
I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good resource for the first thing you want to read if you haven&amp;rsquo;t written anything in compilers.
Also I already read quite &lt;a href="https://glyphack.com/compiler-resources/">few resources about compilers&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am going to read the sequel, Write a compiler in go. That should have new stuff for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I liked the idea that the book had code examples and step by step added everything.
It was good since you can see exactly what next few sections are implementing and decide to skip it.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the amount of test code in the book.
It was repetitive and obvious.
Specially writing every single assert by hand vs snapshot testing.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>